welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive in this video we're going to be
Kdenlive在这段视频中我们将成为
creating a picture-in-picture effect
创建画中画效果
where we'll have a main video playing
在那里我们将播放一段主视频
and then we'll overlay another smaller
然后我们将覆盖另一个较小的
video overtop of that so you can follow
视频覆盖在上面 这样你就可以跟随
along I'm just going to download from
接下来 我将从
pixabay.com I'm gonna change my search
我要更改我的搜索结果
to video and I'll just search jungle and
到录像带 我只会搜索丛林
there's a few videos I'm just going to
有几个视频我要去看看
download to use this first ones a video
下载使用此首个视频
of a parent and so I'll just click free
所以我只需点击免费
download and we'll download up to the
下载 我们将最多下载
720 so it downloads faster and renders
720 因此下载速度更快 渲染速度更快
faster so I'm down only this 1280 by 720
更快 所以我只下降了1280%到720%
it is Creative Commons 0 it's by SEF
这是知识共享0 由SEF出品
alone are so appreciate this oh it has
独自一人是如此感激这一点 哦 它已经
audio too cool and I'm gonna go back so
音频太酷了 我要回去了
we appreciate Cephalonia for uploading
我们非常感谢Cephalia上传
this and then I'm gonna download this
这个 然后我要下载这个
one here that's a like a beach seascape
这里有一张就像海滩海景
buy cover free footage and it's also
购买免费封面素材 它也是
Creative Commons 0 so we'll go ahead and
知识共享空间0 所以我们将继续并
click free download down over the 720
在720上点击免费下载
version and and we have these two video
版本和我们有这两个视频
files so I'm gonna pause this will
文件 所以我要暂停这个文件
minimize and I'm bring this in the
最小化 我要把这个带进
kdenlive I'm gonna do it this time by
Kdenlive我这次要做的就是
just going to my downloads folder
正在转到我的下载文件夹
finding those files that were downloaded
查找已下载的那些文件
like the parrot I'll left click and drag
就像鹦鹉一样 我会左键点击并拖动
it into the project bin and then I'll
把它放进项目箱 然后我会
grab the other one which is this
抓起另一个 就是这个
seascape perfect
完美的海景
now what I want to do I'll just I want
现在我想做的就是我只想
the seascape to be my that whichever you
无论你是谁 海景都是我的
want to have your main large footage you
想让你的主要大镜头
want to put that on video track 1 so I'm
想把这首歌放到第一首录像带上 所以我
gonna left click this seascape and bring
我要左键点击这幅海景并带来
it down to video track 1 start it all
它下降到视频轨道1开始它的一切
the way at 0 and I'm gonna come down
在0点的路上 我要下来
here and resize a little bit so I can
在这里稍微调整一下大小 这样我就可以
see my timeline better and then I'm
更好地看到我的时间线 然后我
gonna grab this video of the parrot and
我要抓起这段鹦鹉的视频
put it on a video track 2 then we can
把它放到录像带2上 然后我们就可以
see this video if the parrot is quite a
看这个视频 如果鹦鹉是一个相当大的
bit longer it's if we look up at the top
如果我们抬头看顶部 时间会更长一些
there it's about almost 45 seconds
差不多有45秒了
whereas this seascape is only about 14
而这幅海景只有14幅左右
seconds so I want to just resize this in
几秒钟 所以我想调整一下大小
the past we've done the razor tool we
过去我们做的剃须刀工具
can click the razor and just go
可以点击剃须刀就可以走了
the very end then left click and cut and
然后左键点击并剪切最后一端
go to select tool click and delete
转到选择工具 然后单击并删除
another way we can do that if I hit
另一种方法就是如果我击中了
control Z and undo that cut we can just
按住Z键并撤消该剪切 我们只需
go to the end of this video and we can
转到这段视频的结尾 我们可以
just hover until we get to this little
一直盘旋到我们到了这个小地方
arrow resize and I can resize this
箭头调整大小 我可以调整这个的大小
parrot clip all the way down and that's
鹦鹉夹子一直往下 这就是
just gonna clip it from the end it's
我只想把它从最后剪下来
gonna clip wherever wherever this ends
在这一切结束的任何地方都会被剪断
at so come right down to there and then
在那里 然后直接下来
it'll snap to end right at about 14 just
它会在14点左右突然结束
a little over 14 seconds so my whole
14秒多一点 所以我的整个
project is the same length so now if I
项目的长度相同 所以现在如果我
play it's going to play just the parent
播放它将只播放家长
and we'll probably hear the audio oh the
我们很可能会听到音频哦
audio is on the parrot clip maybe
也许鹦鹉的片段里有音频
there's no audio I thought for sure I
没有声音 我以为我肯定
heard some audio somewhere else I don't
我在别的地方听到了一些我没有听到的声音
see any audio on this so neither clip
在这上面看不到任何音频 所以
has audio which is fine but we see we're
有音频 这很好 但我们看到
not seeing this if we were to switch if
如果我们交换的话 我看不到这一点
these were to switch places and we put
这些是互换位置 我们把
the parrot down here and then this
鹦鹉在这下面 然后是这个
whatever video is on the higher video
更高的视频上有什么视频
track the higher number video track gets
跟踪获得的较高编号的视频轨道
displayed first so now if we play and we
首先展示 所以现在如果我们演奏 我们
see the beach seascape video but since
看海滩海景视频 但因为
we want the parrot to be on top we do
我们想让鹦鹉在上面 我们真的想
this and then we just want to apply a
然后 我们只想应用一个
transform like we've done in the past
像我们过去所做的那样转型
tutorials so we come over here to crop
教程 所以我们来这里裁剪
and transform we drag transform we put
变换我们拖拽变换我们放在
it on top of the parrot clip and it
它在鹦鹉夹子的顶部 它
brings up these options we can then
提出了这些选项 然后我们可以
transform and change this and it puts
变换和改变这一点 它就会把
this box around at this red box so we
这个盒子在这个红色的盒子里 所以我们
can actually just click these corners
实际上只需点击这些角
and drag it down and now we've got this
然后把它拖下来 现在我们就有了这个
little parrot down in the bottom right
右下角的小鹦鹉
hand corner so now if we play it'll play
手角 所以现在如果我们玩它就会玩
both of them at once so play the parrot
他们两个同时出现 所以就像鹦鹉一样
clip and it'll show kind of the beach
剪辑一下 它会显示出海滩的样子
and we can actually move this too maybe
我们实际上也可以把这个移走 也许
it'd be better to have in the top right
最好是放在右上角
corner so we can see what's going on so
角落里 这样我们就能看到发生了什么
that's how you do video in video and
这就是你在视频中制作视频的方式
then we can also add in if we wanted to
然后 如果我们想要添加 也可以添加
we can add in just a picture if I go
如果我去了 我们可以加一张照片
what's a good picture I have I have a
我有一张好照片 我有一张
picture here of a guy falling this is
这张照片是一个人掉下来 这是
just a what's open it up here so I can
只是什么把它打开了 这样我就可以
show you it's just a picture like a JPEG
向你展示这只是一张像JPEG的图片
is just a JPEG image of like a person
只是一个像一个人的JPEG图像
kind of falling and so it's not a video
有点坠落 所以这不是一段视频
of clip at all
剪辑的全部内容
but we can also just drag in this video
但我们也可以拖着这段视频
clip so we can put it on video 3 I'm
这样我们就可以把它放到录像带3上了
sorry not video clip this picture and
对不起 没有视频剪辑这张照片和
now it'll just play this picture for
现在它只会播放这张图片
like 5 seconds if we double click we can
比如5秒 如果我们双击我们就可以
change the duration or we can go to the
更改持续时间 否则我们可以转到
end like we did with the video and just
就像我们在视频中做的那样结束 然后
scroll or drag and keep it so now this
滚动或拖动并保持它 现在这个
is the same length and now we see it's
是相同的长度 现在我们看到它是
kind of overlaid on top too we can see
上面也覆盖了一层 我们可以看到
the video on the side we can drag and
边上的视频我们可以拖动和
drop a transform on top of this as well
在这个上面也放一个变换
and then we can transform it oops why is
然后我们可以把它转换成哦为什么？
it going over there oh ok so it's
它在那边 哦 好的 所以它是
drawing it a box around the whole thing
在整件事周围画一个方框
is as a transparent transparent on both
是作为透明的透明的
sides but we can still just resize this
两边 但我们仍然可以调整大小
and confuse me for a second there so if
把我搞糊涂了一秒钟 所以如果
we want this and if we wanted it to in
我们想要这个 如果我们想要的话
fact what we could do is only have its
事实上 我们所能做的只有它的
display for it for a moment so by that I
为它展示一阵子 所以我
what I mean is let's say we're playing
我的意思是 让我们假设我们在玩
we have our video clip of our parrot
我们有我们的鹦鹉的视频剪辑
going here and then when it gets to that
到了这里 然后到了那个地方
point of the video it displays this
它显示的视频点如下
picture and then it goes away so and
一张照片 然后它就这样消失了
then we can move that to any point in
然后我们可以将其移动到任何点
the in the video clip and we could also
在视频剪辑中 我们还可以
do that same thing with the with a
用一个
parrot if we scale this down a little
鹦鹉 如果我们把规模缩小一点
bit more or not if we shorten it then
如果我们把它缩短一点 多一点或少一点
we'll see it'll play we'll have the
我们会看到它会播放我们会有
picture come on for a short while then
图片来一小会儿 然后
as soon as the picture goes off we can
一旦画面消失 我们就可以
have the parrot go away as well and yeah
让鹦鹉也走吧 是的
it creates that that's a new video in
它创造了一个新的视频
video or picture in picture effect we
视频或图片在图片效果
could also have the picture be the
也可以把照片变成
static background if we wanted to and
静态背景 如果我们愿意
then resize the beach footage to make it
然后调整海滩镜头的大小
smaller so I think you're getting the
所以我想你会得到
idea of how that works if you have any
如果你有任何
questions comments please leave them
问题评论请留下
below go ahead and like and subscribe if
下面继续 喜欢和订阅 如果
you found this video informative and
你发现这段视频内容丰富
I'll catch you on the next video
下一段视频我会和你见面的